T. STUART SCHAFER

Email: stuart schafer@hotmail.com (704) 779-7890

https://stuartschafer.github.io/Portfolio/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/stuart-schafer/

I'm a full-stack web developer with an intense passion for coding, creating, and maintaining web applications. I also have more than 16 years work experience in contract sales, project management, and customer service roles in which I maximized company profit through customer relationships and knowledge of computer programs.

EDUCATION

UNC Chapel Hill Chapel Hill, NC 2017

A 24-week vigorous coding Boot Camp in which I created full-stack web applications. Skills learned are Node JS, React, JavaScript, MongoDB, MySQL, Sequelize, Express, APIs, AJAX requests, GitHub, jQuery, Axios, Bootstrap, Material UI, HTML5, CSS, Firebase, Handlebars, Data-Tables, ShineJS, and Inquirer.

UNC Charlotte Charlotte, NC 1995-1998

Coursework toward Bachelor of Science, Mechanical Engineering

Appalachian State University Boone, NC 1994

Bachelor of Science degree, Industrial Technology with concentration in Manufacturing, Minor in Business

APPLICATIONS BUILT

Planet Venn

- Created components, generated APIs, and made requests to a database on a team for a logic-based educational game based on a Venn diagram. We used React, NodeJS, MongoDB, JavaScript, Express, Passport, Axios, APIs, GitHub, HTML5, CSS, JQuery, and Material UI.
- https://morning-hamlet-93020.herokuapp.com/ https://github.com/stuartschafer/Planet-Venn

Safe Keeper

- Constructed a database, gathered/sent information to that database, and designed APIs for inventory management as part of a team. Inventory items could be added, deleted, and fully edited for various properties to keep track of valuables. We utilized Node JS, MySQL, JavaScript, APIs, Express, Passport, GitHub, jQuery, HTML5, CSS, and ShineJS.
- https://safe-stream-99507.herokuapp.com/
- To view an example user and items, sign in using email: stu@mail.com, pw: 12345

News Scraper

- Developed a server and client app that scrapes "The Onion" website and allows users to save news articles and add/edit comments about each article. I utilized Node JS, MongoDB, JavaScript, Express, APIs, GitHub, Handlebars, Cheerio, jQuery, HTML5, and CSS.
- https://the-onion-news-scraper.herokuapp.com/ https://github.com/stuartschafer/News-Scraper

WORK EXPERIENCE

Interwire Products Charlotte, NC 04/2012 - 10/2016

Inside Sales, Customer Service, Order Entry, Inventory Control

- Purchased wire from domestic and international mills, verifying the products met proper ANSI specs
- Managed accounts to ensure inventory was delivered on time and correctly

S.L. Bagby Company Charlotte, NC 10/1998 – 11/2011

Project Management, Inside Sales, Customer Service, Order Entry

- Provided full account support for a multi-million dollar national lighting account.
- Reviewed submittal contracts and other documents to identify areas of concern and to find solutions.
- Designed programs for inventory & sales to increase productivity and decrease waste. (Kaizen projects)